[
    {
        "question": "What tool is specifically used to draw vertical and oblique lines?",
        "choices": ["Triangle", "Divider", "Tape rule/Pull-push rule", "Baluster detail"],
        "answer": "Triangle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument allows you to divide lines or distances into equal parts?",
        "choices": ["AutoCAD computer", "Divider", "Masking tape", "Medium"],
        "answer": "Divider"
    },
    {
        "question": "To mark distances and measure, which tool would you use?",
        "choices": ["Medium", "Technical Pen", "Tape rule/Pull-push rule", "Templates"],
        "answer": "Tape rule/Pull-push rule"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the flat plastic guide with standard symbols used for drawing plans.",
        "choices": ["Triangle", "Protractor", "Elevation", "Templates"],
        "answer": "Templates"
    },
    {
        "question": "What device is used to secure drawing paper on a drawing board?",
        "choices": ["AutoCAD computer", "Masking tape", "Medium", "Compass"],
        "answer": "Masking tape"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the standard grade of pencil typically used in architectural drawings?",
        "choices": ["Elevation", "Masking tape", "Medium", "Parallel rule"],
        "answer": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument is ideal for drawing arcs and circles?",
        "choices": ["T-square", "Protractor", "Medium", "Compass"],
        "answer": "Compass"
    },
    {
        "question": "What tool is employed to draw horizontal lines and assist with triangle guides?",
        "choices": ["T-square", "Masking tape", "Medium", "Protractor"],
        "answer": "T-square"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of transparent paper is used for blueprint reproduction?",
        "choices": ["Tracing paper", "Triangular scale", "Parallel rule", "AutoCAD computer"],
        "answer": "Tracing paper"
    },
    {
        "question": "For adjusting the scale of measurements and transferring them to drawing paper, which tool is used?",
        "choices": ["Tracing paper", "Triangular scale", "Masking tape", "Compass"],
        "answer": "Triangular scale"
    },
    {
        "question": "What instrument can be used instead of the standard drawing board and T-square?",
        "choices": ["Compass", "Triangular scale", "Parallel rule", "AutoCAD computer"],
        "answer": "Parallel rule"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a high-tech device used for drawing purposes?",
        "choices": ["Tracing paper", "Triangular scale", "Compass", "AutoCAD computer"],
        "answer": "AutoCAD computer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What tool is utilized to clean smudges of pencil and ink lines?",
        "choices": ["Eraser", "Technical Pen", "Protractor", "Penknife or Pencil Sharpener"],
        "answer": "Eraser"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument is employed for inking mechanical lines?",
        "choices": ["Eraser", "Technical Pen", "Divider", "Compass"],
        "answer": "Technical Pen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is used to measure angles in degrees?",
        "choices": ["Eraser", "Technical Pen", "Protractor", "French curve"],
        "answer": "Protractor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tool is designed for sharpening pencils to the desired lead point?",
        "choices": ["Eraser", "Divider", "Protractor", "Penknife or Pencil Sharpener"],
        "answer": "Penknife or Pencil Sharpener"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a thin metal sheet used to protect other drawing lines while erasing pencil and inked lines?",
        "choices": ["Erasing shield", "Sandpaper block", "French curve", "Leroy lettering pen"],
        "answer": "Erasing shield"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument assists in shaping pencil lead into a conical point?",
        "choices": ["Divider", "Sandpaper block", "Compass", "Leroy lettering pen"],
        "answer": "Sandpaper block"
    },
    {
        "question": "What tool is used to set a line degree angle?",
        "choices": ["Baluster detail", "Sandpaper block", "French curve", "Leroy lettering pen"],
        "answer": "French curve"
    },
    {
        "question": "What alternative tool can be used for sharpening a pencil to the desired point?",
        "choices": ["Perspective", "Sandpaper block", "French curve", "Leroy lettering pen"],
        "answer": "Sandpaper block"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of diagram illustrates the arrangement of rooms, doors, windows, and other features in a building?",
        "choices": ["Elevation", "Floor plan", "Perspective", "Location plan"],
        "answer": "Floor plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What view provides the top perspective of the site or lot for the proposed construction?",
        "choices": ["Roof plan", "Floor plan", "Perspective", "Location plan"],
        "answer": "Location plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What drawing provides the outline and dimensions of the proposed building along with its placement on the property?",
        "choices": ["Baluster detail", "Floor plan", "Site development plan", "Location plan"],
        "answer": "Site development plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What drawing shows the front or side view of a building, including its design, height, and materials?",
        "choices": ["Elevation", "Floor plan", "Perspective", "Location plan"],
        "answer": "Elevation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of drawing shows the interior of the building in either cross-section or longitudinal section?",
        "choices": ["Section", "Roof plan", "Reflected ceiling plan", "Elevation"],
        "answer": "Section"
    },
    {
        "question": "What plan indicates the placement and positioning of lighting fixtures in a house?",
        "choices": ["Elevation", "Roof plan", "Reflected ceiling plan", "Baluster detail"],
        "answer": "Reflected ceiling plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What detail represents the vertical railing along a staircase or balcony?",
        "choices": ["Perspective", "Divider", "Reflected ceiling plan", "Baluster detail"],
        "answer": "Baluster detail"
    },
    {
        "question": "What drawing provides the complete design plan of a house's ceiling?",
        "choices": ["Section", "Roof plan", "Reflected ceiling plan", "Baluster detail"],
        "answer": "Reflected ceiling plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What plan outlines the roof and indicates major lines such as ridges, valleys, hips, and openings?",
        "choices": ["Roof plan", "Doors and windows schedule", "Kitchen detail", "Toilet and bath detail"],
        "answer": "Roof plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What schedule details the complete specifications of doors and windows, including their width, height, type, materials, and quantity?",
        "choices": ["Kitchen detail", "Doors and windows schedule", "Elevation", "Insulation"],
        "answer": "Doors and windows schedule"
    },
    {
        "question": "What drawing depicts the kitchen floor plan with all necessary specifications?",
        "choices": ["Kitchen detail", "Elevation", "Insulation", "Blueprint"],
        "answer": "Kitchen detail"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which diagram illustrates the toilet and bath with complete details of their features?",
        "choices": ["Location plan", "Doors and windows schedule", "Toilet and bath detail", "Perspective"],
        "answer": "Toilet and bath detail"
    },
    {
        "question": "What term refers to a reproduced version of architectural plans and layouts?",
        "choices": ["Kitchen detail", "Location plan", "Elevation drawing", "Blueprint"],
        "answer": "Blueprint"
    },
    {
        "question": "What describes the overhead surface of a room or the material used to cover it?",
        "choices": ["Scaling", "Elevation drawing", "Ceiling", "Code"],
        "answer": "Ceiling"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a set of accepted laws and regulations that guide procedures or behaviors in specific situations or professions?",
        "choices": ["Perspective", "Elevation drawing", "Elevation", "Code"],
        "answer": "Code"
    },
    {
        "question": "What term describes the exterior and interior details of a building, often shown as a perpendicular projection from the floor plan to reveal vertical details?",
        "choices": ["Scaling", "Elevation drawing", "Ceiling", "Perspective"],
        "answer": "Elevation drawing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What term is used for the process of enlarging or reducing a drawing with an architectâ€™s scale?",
        "choices": ["Scaling", "Insulation", "Location plan", "Kitchen detail"],
        "answer": "Scaling"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the first things an architect must do before designing a building is to read the building codes. Why?",
        "choices": ["To make your design futuristic", "To give good luck to the owner of the house", "To meet the requirements of zoning laws", "All of the above"],
        "answer": "To meet the requirements of zoning laws"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why should walls with window openings not be less than 2.00 m from the lot line of the fence?",
        "choices": ["Adjacent houses should not be at least 4.00 m apart", "To maintain good airflow", "To give more natural sunlight", "All of the above"],
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "For constructing a one-story wooden or frame house, why is it that the height of the floor plan from the ground should not be less than 1.50 m?",
        "choices": ["It is because of the building code", "It is because most designers made it that way", "It is because most people like to have this kind of design", "All of the above"],
        "answer": "It is because of the building code"
    }
]
